hi friends today i am going to do a
review on htfc ergo optima secure health
insurance policy
in this video i am going to talk about
what one should know one must know
before buying this particular policy
this video is not a
product promotion and i'm not a health
insurance agent
nor i am a qualified advisor
so why i am doing this video
actually i was looking for purchasing
a health insurance policy for myself
uh although i have one from
the company
uh i started searching youtube videos
and then started reading
various reviews to find out what is the
best policy for me
when i came across multiple youtube
videos what i found
is basically most of the videos are
talking the
positive sides of the policies
they are talking about the high level
features and benefits
but they don't talk much about the
challenges or the problems associated
with these policies
so i thought i would
use this video to convey what are the
challenges associated with these
policies
uh most of these videos are basically
promotions possibly
and then they are
created by the advisors in search of new
buyers
they give you
feedback saying that this is the best
policy to
buy and then they will recommend you to
go and buy it immediately
history of circo coming to the company
there is no doubt that this is one of
the best
insurance companies
in india
and they are backed by a hsc group
so they are financially very strong
reputed and then they they come in top
for many parameters within the
insurance industry right
uh however in this particular video uh
i'm going to talk about the optima
secure policy
[Music]
itself
uh before we get into the challenges
first we will look at the
key features of this policy
it gives you a 2x cover from day one
which means if you have taken a 10 lakh
some insured
you are eligible to climb up to 20 lakh
from day one
it also gives you a
50 additional cover
after first year renewal and then it
gives you a hundred percent additional
some insured cover after secondary
renewal
so they have a feature called
plus benefit to provide this additional
fifty percent and additional hundred 100
cover
they also give you a restore benefit so
in case of a client
they fill the remaining uh some insured
value through this restore benefit
so by using the secure benefit plus
benefit and restore benefit
uh the prospectors and brochure clients
and their
agents and the
staff who are on the calls claim that
this gives you 4x coverage right let's
see whether it is really 4x cover or not
it also has a good feature
called aggregate detectable suppose you
want to take
payment from your side then they will
give you 25 percent reduction in the
premium which is a good feature for
those who can afford a front payment of
25000 rupees
uh
then it also covers to a larger extent
the non-medical and consumables
so you will not have surprises while the
claims are getting passed
it also gives you a
60 days pre-hospitalization and 190 days
post-hospitalization
coverage which i would say one among the
best in the
industry
and they also give you a
preventive health checkup
feature
so
if if it is a family floater policy the
family members they can decide who can
take maybe one or two people in a year
and avoid this health checkup
it also provides
coverage for ice treatment
so i would say in a nutshell it gives
you a good amount of benefits through
the policy
however the question is
is it really forex coverage as they
claim right so let's look at i don't
think uh that's the fact
so point points that we should think are
we should uh question
uh
how much of these claims are true right
so the 2x cover our
3x cover through plus benefit our 4x
cover through restore benefit they say
that it comes at no extra cost right
we know that there is nothing called
free in this world everything is paid
for
so
in your premium you are basically paying
for all these benefits whether you like
it or not so
your base some insured may be 10 lakh
rupees but when they say forex benefit
to the extent of 40 lakhs the premium
has been
increased to that extent right so you'll
have to pay for that so you need to
carefully choose how much of the
coverage is required for you
uh when you see the
brochure you may not find much of
information about any policy not just
the optima secure
so when i try to understand more about
this policy through policy wordings
document and the prospectus document i
found certain things
uh
in a very uncomfortable
position right
for example the
key benefits what they are talking the
secure benefit which provides the 2x
cover and then the plus benefit which
gives you the additional 100 some
insured coverage
and then the
automatic restore benefit which gives
you another 100 percentage by which you
are able to get
2x3 x and 4x cover all of them have been
put under optional
right
which was not
giving some kind of comfort right
these were supposed to be part of the
main cover itself not as an optional
cover
the reason why it puts people in
uncomfortable
situation is because
will there be a
situation where some of these benefits
get removed later from the plan and you
will end up
having a lesser cover right we don't
know actually i try to
uh
get an answer from hdfc but
unfortunately i didn't get a response
from them
uh
why these covers are optional is
something we don't know
and
the reason why the doubts are coming up
is because
in one of in the same document
there is a specific class which says the
uh with the approval from irdai
the terms and
the premiums can be revised right so we
do we do not know whether the secure
benefit plus benefit
and then the automatic restore benefits
uh will be retained throughout the
lifetime of the policy or they will
remove it at some
at a later stage is something we do not
know
so i tried to get a answer on the email
but unfortunately i did not get a
response from them
uh so secure benefit is a very
straightforward feature right so you
have a some insured of x value
from day one you get 2x3 coverage so
straightforward feature
the plus benefit is i would say a little
bit of trick
most of the other policies gives you a
no claim bonus so if there is no claim
in a specific year you get some amount
of extra coverage coming in through no
claim bonus right
whereas this plus benefits gives you a
additional
insured coverage
uh even though if you are making a claim
right irrespective of making claims that
is the reason why i feel that they are
not using the word ncb
uh rather they use as a plus benefit
right so
even if you have a claim
you are eligible to get 50 percent uh
some insured as a plus benefit after
first year in evil and 100
um
some ensure additional sum insured
as a plus benefit after second year uh
renewal
but the catch is that uh all these are
all taken into account from day one
premium itself right so when you make a
first premium itself
all these are all included so the 50
percent are 100 whatever they are taking
it
however you are not getting that benefit
right so you have to wait for the
second
premium
then you get 50 percent
benefit getting covered
similarly after making the second year
renewal that's the third premium you
make a third premium
then you get 100
of the plus benefit getting added to
your overall uh usability right
basically it's a trick
restore benefit uh again this is uh
it looks as if that they are giving the
4x cover
but i find it uh
it is not exactly a forex benefit
uh what happens you cannot get the
restore benefit on your first claim in
every year right so the first claim
will not have a restore benefit uh
amount included ah so and then if there
is anything left in a year it will not
get carried forward so every year
restore benefit will get added
and that will kick in only after your
second claim in that particular year
right and they also have a
class which says a single climb has a
limit
how much is the maximum claim can happen
right so that is only to the tune of
some insured plus the 2x cure benefit
and the plus benefit if you are eligible
after paying those second year and third
year premium
and it cannot exit that right
which means even though if the secure
restore benefit comes into the picture
uh in a single claim you will not be
able to
get that amount
approved right so i have a small
calculation when you see that you will
come to know
what i am talking about
so let us use a small illustration to
talk about
the challenges associated with this
forex cover right
uh let's look at first here right in the
first year you are not eligible for the
plus benefit because that will kick in
only after the first year renewal rate
let's say there is a first claim you are
making uh and then assume that you have
taken us some insured of 10 lakh rupees
right so your basic summary insured is
10 lakh rupees
and because of the secure benefit you
will be having a total kitty of 20 lakhs
so your first climb amount is 5 lakhs
and you will you are fully eligible to
get this
amount approved so you are not paying
anything from your pocket
and then let's say there is a second
claim which is 25 like comes in
right so you have a you already
used 5 lakh from the admissible uh the
total kitty and then you have left over
five lakhs
and the secure benefit and lack is there
uh now because the second claim is being
made
the restore benefit kicks in right so
the balance between the whatever money
climbed earlier and then the uh
the restore benefit the file gets added
here so it becomes 20 lakhs total kitty
and your claim is 25 lakhs right
so the maximum amount that will be
approved will be only 20 lakhs you will
have to pay from your pocket five lakh
rupees for this claim
now in the same year let's say there is
a third climb
and then that is 10 lakh rupees claim
uh now there is no basic sum insured it
is already
exhausted and there is no secure benefit
is also that is also exhausted what you
are left with is only the through the
restore benefit there is a 5 lakh rupees
is available that will be
approved for you so the balance by lack
you will have to pay from your pocket
right so
is it really a forex benefit honestly
not right so essentially
uh using this restore benefit there some
some kind of restrictions happens which
i would say it's not more than
uh
3x benefit in an overall year
not actually a forex benefit right
now let's look at the second year
where you get the
uh fifty percent plus benefit coming in
after the first year annual right so we
use the same five lakh twenty five lakh
and ten lakh now because this plus
benefit comes into the picture now the
second claim earlier you are paying five
lakh from your pocket that is not
required right that is covered through
the plus benefit
uh in the third claim as it happened
earlier
uh you have a leftover kitty of only um
five lakhs so you have to pay five lakh
from your pocket
so
again it is not a completely a 4x
coverage right
then let's look at a third year
illustration like three what happens
after you making the
third premium basically there are two
two renewals are paid for right let's
again use the same 5 lakh 25 lakh and 30
lakh
claims
uh here what happens because you get the
100 additional sum insured through the
plus benefit which is the no claim bonus
in other name is called plus benefit
uh so you are not going to pay anything
from your pocket so all your expenses
are getting covered
right
however here the cash is
suppose assume that let's say the second
claim becomes a 35 lakh claim not a 24
claim
now what happens uh you although your
kitty has got
35 lakh money
uh you will not get that right
because they have a
limitation right and how much is the
maximum claim amount
so you cannot have a single claim more
than some insured let's say in this case
it is
10 lakhs and then secure benefit is
another 10 lakhs the plus benefit is
another 10 lakhs in the in the third
year right
uh so the maximum amount permissible in
this claim is 30 lakh so you will still
pay
uh pay for 5 lakh from your pocket right
so
it is completely not forex
so if you have a high uh
amount of claim coming in
you might end up paying from your pocket
now let's look at this health checkup
the benefits right actually i would
prefer that these companies make this
completely optional and then pass on
that
the premium benefit to me
the reason is
look at
for a different amount of some insured
uh you are eligible to
do a health in health check up to a
certain value right so let's say for
example you are opting for a
10 lakh some insured
and as a family let's say you have two
adults and one child or two child
uh maybe for a child you will not do the
health checkup let's say for two adults
you want to do
and you have five thousand rupees to do
that right
uh in 2022 this year uh you are
you may be able to do it at 5000 rupees
uh your premium is going to go up right
so every year your premium will increase
because your age keeps increasing and
we have also seen
with ird approvals uh they also increase
the premium
beyond what is
stipulated today right
uh and then the health checkup cost also
will go up right
today whatever health checkup you are
able to do at 5000 rupees can you do at
the same price point after two years
three years the question will be no
right so it will keep increasing but
here you have a limitation of 5000
rupees under this particular 10 lakh sum
insured right
so the limit will stay constant but your
premiums will go up and can two adults
complete their health checkup for next
five to ten years within 5000 rupees
limit per year the answer is a clear no
if you go to some of the good hospitals
and try to do a
comprehensive health checkup for one
individual
that alone can
range anywhere between
6 000 to ten thousand rupees
for one person right that is in 2022
rates
assume down the line uh three year four
year later you want to do for two adults
a comprehensive
health checkup
uh in those kind of good hospitals then
you might end up paying around 25 30 000
rupees whereas your limit is only uh
5000 rupees so definitely you are going
to pay a lot of money from your pockets
towards this particular benefit so
honestly speaking you are not covered
completely right it's only a part that
you will be covered
uh as you go
many years down the line right so i
would say this is actually not a
beneficial
feature you must typically ignore and
then if there is a possibility of
getting without this that will be ideal
uh one of the biggest let down right
maybe you can ignore many other things
in the whole
policy however there is a room rent
cabin in this particular policy right
so i was trying to figure out how what
kind of rooms are available with these
hospitals and then what are the rates
for these hospitals right
so i came across one of the document in
the internet
which gives the rates of different
hospitals
these numbers may not be correct
uh may be right or may not be right so
you i would
suggest you to
get it verified at your yourself right
but there is a fair possibility the
rates may be in the in a
plus or minus range
right uh
in this particular policy uh the
eligibility if your call
some insured is up to 50 lakhs right
then you are eligible to have without
any limit on single a0 right but if you
go to these hospitals you have uh so
this is one what is called this the one
it's not having any name is your single
private ac room and then they have
different nomenclatures like deluxe
executives suit room super deluxe so
they have different different names have
been provided right
my understanding is i also verified with
many other people
that in this policy
only this where it is not year marked as
a
deluxe acr suit or executive you are
eligible right if it is up to 49 lakh
coverage right 50 lakh and demo i think
they are allowing you to have a
different
higher rules right
now this is a big letdown
so why i am saying this is a big letdown
now let's have a
look at the calculation how it this can
be a problem for you
uh so i have done a small match around
same rates i have taken
and i am also considering let's say that
you end up
in the hospital
for about 15 days right and you don't
get a single private e0
if the hospital says that room is not
available you can only opt for a
deluxe ac or executive or suit room you
can't go and fight with them right so
you will end up anyway taking that room
at that critical juncture and
the stfc are go will only provide you
the difference between the unload single
private ac and then the higher room what
you are going for right
now i have taken a 10 increase on the
room rent on a yearly basis so for 15
days if you are staying the difference
in amount i have put it in this column
right in this row right so for example
in 2022 if you are taking a deluxe ac
room
and then for 15 days you will have to
pay 55 000 rupees from your packet
right
and for every uh
further years you will see that this
rate will keep on increasing right so
depending upon what kind of room you are
choosing uh you might end up paying from
your pocket somewhere between a little
over a lakh
to all the way to six lakh plus
right so
you cannot predict which room you will
get and then how long you are going to
be there in the hospital
so how much is the
claim amount will be approved uh so the
difference will have to be paid from
your packet right
so if you are opting this policy
uh ensure that there is a enough amount
of money is available
uh to pay for this uh difference right
so this is what i wanted to cover uh i
found that this policy had a lot of
challenges which people don't talk i
thought people must know and they should
be aware of what they are
what they are buying right
so thanks for patiently listening
and viewing this video
i hope this is useful and uh if you like
it please
like this video and share with your
friends
uh thank you so much if there are
anything um wrong information you can
put it in the comment
uh see you soon thank you